Guide to the Eric Knight Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings, Series I
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Stories
      - "The Ten Gallon Hat": typescript drafts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 288-91)
        See also: Oversize, Box 18, folder 386
      - "The Two-Fifty Hat": Liberty, 1930 Jun 28 (Box 13, Folder 292)
      - "That Damfool, Josephine": Argosy, 1938 May 21 (Box 13, Folder 293)
      - "Time for the Pieman"
        See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 387
      - "The Truth About Rudolf Hess": typescripts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 294)
      - "The Yorkshireman Flies Again"
        See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 388
      - "War News--Secret": New Yorker, 1941 Mar 29 (Box 13, Folder 295)
- Personal Papers, Series II
  - Architectural drawings
    - House designed by Eric Knight, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 296)
  - Artwork
    - Cartoons, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 297-301)
    - Christmas cards, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 302)
    - Miscellaneous studies, 1933, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 303)
    - Portraits, 1910-35, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 304-08)
    - Sketchbook, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - "Sketches of Yorkshire characters-- Sam Small", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 310)
  - Certificates
    - Birth certificate, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 311)
    - Labour certificate, 1910 (Box 14, Folder 312)
    - Naturalization certificate, 1942 (Box 14, Folder 313)
    - Swimming certificates, 1908-09 (Box 14, Folder 314)
  - Correspondence
    - Broadhurst, Ian, 1941 May 18 (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - Clemens, Cyril, 1941 Apr 28
    - Darbyshire, Percy W., 1941 Apr 9
    - Hanbridge, W. D., 1941 Jun 11
    - Hanson, Aquilla B., 1941 Jun 4
    - Hegone, Wanda, 1941 Apr 21
    - Jackson, Ethel, n.d.
    - McCormick,---, 1936 Feb
    - "Percy", 1941 Jul 2 (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - Pilkington, Walter, 1941 Apr 7
    - "Stina", 1941 Aug
    - Wheeler, Margaret, 1941 Jul 23
  - Interviews and quotes
    - [ Iowa City Gazette ], [1941?] (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - The Monetary Times, 1942 Mar 14 (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - The New York Times Book Review
      See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 389
    - Quote, 1942 Aug 3 (Box 14, Folder 319)
    - Soviet Russia Today, 1941 Nov (Box 14, Folder 320)
    - The Wellesley Review, 1941 Oct (Box 14, Folder 321)
  - Knight, Edmund
    - Appointment as sergeant, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 322)
    - Death notice, 1920
    - Memorial scroll
      See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 390
  - Knight, Frederick
    - Memorial scrolls
      See: Oversize, Box 18, folders 391-392
  - Lectures and teaching
    - Columbia University Extension, Film Study: "The History of the Motion Picture, lecture 4", 1938 Oct 25 (Box 14, Folder 323)
    - Iowa Writer's Workshop: notes, quizzes, and student work, 1941 (Box 14, Folder 324-25)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1926-42, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 326-27)
  - Photographs
    - Creasser, E. Vernon, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 328-29)
      See also: Oversize, Box 18, folder 393
    - Fontaine, Joan, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 330)
    - "Hilda", 1942 (Box 14, Folder 331)
    - Knight, Edmund and Frederick Knight, [1918?] (Box 14, Folder 332)
    - Knight, Eric, 1917-42, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 333-35)
      See also: Oversize, Box 18, folders 394-395
    - Knight, Eric: publicity stills, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 336)
    - Knight, Eric, with dogs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 337)
    - Knight, Eric, with horses, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 338)
    - Knight, Eric and Jere, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 339)
    - Knight, Eric and friends, 1942, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 340)
    - Knight, Frederick, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 341)
      See also: Oversize, Box 18, folder 396
    - McDowall, Roddy, and Lassie (Box 15, Folder 342)
      See: Oversize, Box 18, folder 397
    - Peri, 1932
    - [Pickford], Mary, n.d.
    - Wong, Anna Mae, n.d.
  - World War II
    - Application to Army, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 343)
    - Citation for Legion of Merit: text by Paul Horgan, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 344)
    - "Contents of musette bag"
      - "Africa Film Footage, New York", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 345)
      - African history notes, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 346)
      - Chart of Special Services Operation, 1942 Aug (Box 15, Folder 347)
      - "Hints on Pronouncing Arabic", n.d. (Box 15, Folder 348)
      - Letter of introduction, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 349)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1942, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 350-51)
      - "Morale and Special Services", 1942 Nov 2 (Box 15, Folder 352)
      - Orders, 1942-1943 Jan (Box 15, Folder 353-57)
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 358)
      - Pocket guides: England and Egypt (Box 15, Folder 359)
      - Services of Supply directories, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 360)
    - Poem: "Major Eric Knight," by Lucille Coleman, in Matrix, Little Book 1, 1943 Fall (Box 15, Folder 361)
- Oversize
  - WRITINGS
    - "Lassie Come-Home": Saturday Evening Post, 1938 dec 17 (Box 15, Folder 362)
    - Scroll honoring Lassie, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 363)
    - This Above All movie publicity: Illustrated, 1942 Feb 14 (Box 16, Folder 364)
    - This Above All movie publicity: Life, 1942 Jan 26 (Box 16, Folder 365)
    - "Britain's Black Ghosts": Saturday Evening Post, 1938 May 28 (Box 16, Folder 366)
    - "The British Eat to Win": Saturday Evening Post, 1942 May 16 (Box 16, Folder 367)
    - "Will Peace Bring a United States of Europe?" Saturday Evening Post, 1942 Aug 8 (Box 16, Folder 368)
    - "All Those Beautiful Things": Collier's, 1942 Sep 19 (Box 16, Folder 369)
    - "All Yankees Are Liars": Saturday Evening Post, 1938 Jan 15 (Box 16, Folder 370)
    - "Bison Bill and Johnny Bull": Esquire, 1940 Nov (Box 16, Folder 371)
    - "The Flying Yorkshireman": Maclean's, 1939 Jun 15 (Box 16, Folder 372)
    - "The Flying Yorkshireman": Serialization in The Passing Show, 1938 Aug 13-27 (Box 16, Folder 373-75)
    - "The Flying Yorkshireman": Story, 1937 Jul (Box 16, Folder 376)
    - "I Knew They'd Never Make It": Esquire, 1939 Aug (Box 16, Folder 377)
    - "In a Small Way": Town and Country, 1938 Jun (Box 16, Folder 378)
    - "Mary Ann and the Duke": Esquire, 1937 Dec (Box 17, Folder 379)
    - "Mr. Poots and the Ugly Tyke": Collier's, 1941 Apr 5 (Box 17, Folder 380)
    - "Never Come Monday": Esquire, 1938 Mar (Box 17, Folder 381)
    - "Rifles of the Regiment": Collier's, 1942 Aug 15 (Box 17, Folder 382)
    - "Sam and His Yankee Allies": Saturday Evening Post, 1943 Feb 27 (Box 17, Folder 383)
    - "Sam Small's Better Half": Maclean's, 1940 Jun 1 (Box 17, Folder 384)
    - "Strong in the Arms": Esquire, 1938 Apr (Box 17, Folder 385)
    - "The Ten Gallon Hat": Maclean's, 1939 Oct 1 (Box 18, Folder 386)
    - "Time for the Pieman": Esquire, 1938 Jun (Box 18, Folder 387)
    - "The Yorkshireman Flies Again": Saturday Evening Post, 1941 Dec 20 (Box 18, Folder 388)
  - PERSONAL PAPERS
    - The New York Times Book Review, 1942 Apr 5 (Box 18, Folder 389)
    - Knight, Edmund: Memorial scroll (Box 18, Folder 390)
    - Knight, Frederick: Memorial scrolls, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 391-92)
    - Creasser, Vernon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 393)
    - Knight, Eric, 1934, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 394-95)
    - Knight, Frederick, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 396)
    - McDowall, Roddy, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 397)
    - McDowall, Roddy, with Lassie, n.d.